Laura Guillardín Calvo

PhD student

Focusing both the final BSc and MSc thesis in genetic bioinformatics methods, I acquired skills in forest genomic data analysis and data processing tools. As Cloud Analytics employee I learned how to deal with BigData projects in different scenarios. Currently, the purpose of my PhD project is to assess the genetic effects of applying Continuous Cover Forestry silvicultural approach in non-native conifer UK populations.

www.researchgate.net/profile/Laura Guillardin

Oxford, UK

in linkedin.com/in/laura-guillardín-0b706914b

lauguillardin.github.io

WORK EXPERIENCE

PhD Student in Forest Genetics University of Oxford

09/2019 - Present Plant Sciences Department Oxford, UK

Junior Cloud Data Architect myCloudDoor

09/2018 - 09/2019

Forest Genetics Research Intern Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

11/2017 - 05/2018

Madrid, ES

Madrid, ES

Achievements/Tasks

Department of Systems and Natural Resources.

 Bioinformatics approaches for the genetic analysis of progenies of half siblings of holm oaks, cork oaks and hybrid individuals with the aim of use the plant material in breeding projects focused on the quality of cork.

Forest Genetics Research Intern NEIKER-Tecnalia

09/2016 - 12/2016

Vitoria/Gastéiz, ES

Collaboration in forest genetic research project.

Achievements/Tasks

 Genetic and phenotype analysis of European white oaks populations in the pre-pyrenean area. Structure and Landscape genomics approaches.

1ST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS

Guillardín-Calvo, L., Mora-Márquez, F., Soto, Á. et al. RADdesigner: a workflow to select the optimal sequencing methodology in genotyping experiments on woody plant species. Tree Genetics & Genomes 15, 64 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1007/s11295-019-1372-3

EDUCATION

MSc in Agroforestry Biotechnology Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

09/2017 - 07/2018

Madrid

BSc in Forestry EngineeringUniversidad Politécnica de Madrid.

09/2011 - 07/2017 Madrid

SKILLS

Forest Genetics Genomics Bioinformatics R

Statistics Botany UNIX bash Silviculture

Communication skills Time management

Supervision Molecular Biology GIS

LEADERSHIP ROLES AND VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Executive committee member (Treasurer), Oxford University Basketball Club (06/2020 - 06/2021)

General financial oversight. Oversee and present budgets, accounts and financial statements to the committee. As part of the executive committee, I also participated in the coaches hiring process, including interviews and conditions negotiation.

Pirineos de todos y para todos (07/2015 - 07/2015)

Improvement of infrastructure and environment in a refurbished village of the Pyrenees region. We focused on clear end thinning forest areas surrounding the village.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Emergency First Aid for Fieldworkers (10/2021)

Provide first aid skills in contexts with limited paramedic support including remote and challenging environments.

Data Engineering on Google Cloud Platform Specialization (11/2018)

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/GFF3L 7TFWPGR

Gentree-Evoltree Summer School Course: "From genotypes to phenotypes: assessing forest tree diversity in the wild". Kaunas, Lithuania (06/2018)

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

Climbing Botany Environment Basketball

Conservation Museums Mountain Bike